<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Works on Joe Stoica</title>
    <link>https://joestoica.com/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Works on Joe Stoica</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 21:21:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joestoica.com/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive College Life I: Finance</title>
      <link>https://joestoica.com/work/college_finances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 21:21:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joestoica.com/work/college_finances/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with the idea of writing a post like this for a few months now. There are endless blogs and vlogs offering tips and tricks to students on how to successfully navigate the minefield of being an independent college student for their first time. However, I feel like sharing the various technology and productivity strategies thathave added structure to many aspects of my life, which in turn has allowed me to stress less about life and put more focus on being an organized and motivated student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Recreation: Approximate Bayesian computation for disease outbreaks</title>
      <link>https://joestoica.com/work/mabc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 12:27:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joestoica.com/work/mabc/</guid>
      <description>This post is a summary of the final project that I completed for my Statistical Computing course in my first semester of grad school. The goal of this project was to recreate two figures from a paper authored by Tony and Stumpf, “Simulation-based model selection for dynamical systems in systems and population biology”(which can be found here). This paper uses the approximate bayesian computation (or ABC) algorithm to model a few fairly complex statistical models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing xkcd comics in RStudio</title>
      <link>https://joestoica.com/work/xkcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 18:28:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joestoica.com/work/xkcd/</guid>
      <description>I love the webcomic xkcd, and I look forward to seeing the new comic whenever. The problem is, sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m forgetful and I forget to check the website for the latest comic (or sometimes comics if I&amp;rsquo;m really behind). But luckily for me, I do use RStudio everyday. This made me realize that &amp;ldquo;hey, maybe I should make something so I can able to view xkcd in RStudio.&amp;rdquo; So I did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using 1.6 Million Tweets with a Markov Chain Text Generator</title>
      <link>https://joestoica.com/work/markov_chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 18:18:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joestoica.com/work/markov_chain/</guid>
      <description>During my daily dose of reddit browsing, I came across this post and was subsequently pretty confused. How can an office be THAT high? Amidst my bewilderment, I noticed that it came from the subreddit
SubredditSimulator, and its hilarity immediately grabbed my attention. If you are unfamiliar with how Reddit operates, it is basically a giant forum split into thousands of subcommunities called &amp;ldquo;subreddits.&amp;rdquo; Users are allowed to subscribe to whatever subreddits they want to so they can regularly view its content, create posts in any subreddit, and comment on any post they like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remaking Visualizations from 538</title>
      <link>https://joestoica.com/work/538/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 14:46:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joestoica.com/work/538/</guid>
      <description>Fivethirtyeight is one of my favorite news websites for interesting political articles and insightful sports predictions. Fivethirtyeight is spearheaded by Editor in Chief Nate Silver, the popular statistician who wrote the excellent book, The Signal and the Noise. But what I truly love about Fivethirtyeight is their unbiased and objective approach to their methodology, and how they present their data through their visualizations. They use a fairly clean and minimal style, following the idea of a low data-ink ratio, which is something I try to replicate in my own visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining the 2016 Presidential Election</title>
      <link>https://joestoica.com/work/election_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 18:28:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joestoica.com/work/election_2016/</guid>
      <description>A Leaflet map of the 2016 U.S. Election The United States 2016 presidential election seemed like it would be an easy victory for the DNC&amp;rsquo;s Hillary Clinton over the GOP&amp;rsquo;s Donald Trump.
However, Trump came out the victor, depsite losing the popular vote by three million votes. This election has inspired me to dig deeper into the voting data. Through this investigation, I also wanted to become more familiar with choropleth maps in R, and make them interactive using the leaflet package.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>