<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Joe Stoica</title>
    <link>http://joestoica.com/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Joe Stoica</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 18:28:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://joestoica.com/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing xkcd comics in RStudio</title>
      <link>http://joestoica.com/work/xkcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 18:28:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joestoica.com/work/xkcd/</guid>
      <description>I love the webcomic xkcd, and I look forward to seeing the new comic whenever. The problem is, sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m forgetful and I forget to check the website for the latest comic (or sometimes comics if I&amp;rsquo;m really behind). But luckily for me, I do use RStudio everyday. This made me realize that &amp;ldquo;hey, maybe I should make something so I can able to view xkcd in RStudio.&amp;rdquo; So I did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using 1.6 Million Tweets with a Markov Chain Text Generator</title>
      <link>http://joestoica.com/work/markov_chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 18:18:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://joestoica.com/work/markov_chain/</guid>
      <description>During my daily dose of reddit browsing, I came across this post and was subsequently pretty confused. How can an office be THAT high? Amidst my bewilderment, I noticed that it came from the subreddit
SubredditSimulator, and its hilarity immediately grabbed my attention. If you are unfamiliar with how Reddit operates, it is basically a giant forum split into thousands of subcommunities called &amp;ldquo;subreddits.&amp;rdquo; Users are allowed to subscribe to whatever subreddits they want to so they can regularly view its content, create posts in any subreddit, and comment on any post they like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>